RESUME Nishant Dougall

M: 0412 202 666 | E: nishantdougall@gmail.com

Career Profile

I am a Diploma of Community Services graduate with eight years of experience in the corporate sector, and four years of experience in the community services sector.

I am queer, neuro-diverse, gender diverse, and a person of colour. I have lived experience of psychosocial disability, stigmatization, shame, discrimination, intersectionality. I am trauma-informed and excel in roles requiring strong interpersonal skills, and creative problem-solving.

I have volunteered at Thorne Harbour Health and understand the importance of creating a safe, welcoming, client-centred, strengths-based environment for clients of the Positive Living Centre.

I am a classic Capricorn - hardworking, rational, and constructive. I have stepped away from the corporate world because I am passionate about social justice and eager to work for organizations affecting meaning change.

Key Skills

- Demonstrated sensitivity to the issues facing people living with HIV, men who have sex with men, injecting drug users and other communities at risk, and familiarity with MIPA principles
- Empathetic and compassionate approach to client care
- Knowledgeable about community resources and services for the LGBTIQ+ community in Naarm.
- Strong communication and active listening skills to effectively engage with clients and provide trauma-informed, culturally sensitive, nonjudgemental support
- Strong knowledge of community services available to LGBTQIA+ community in Naarm
- Experience in crisis intervention, de-escalation techniques and trained in Mental Health First Aid
- Collaborative approach to working with interdisciplinary teams and community organizations
- Flexible, adaptable and ability to work effectively independently and collaboratively.
- Proven ability to maintain privacy of confidentiality and set appropriate boundaries
- Strong organizational and time management skills to effectively prioritize and manage caseloads

Education and Training

Diploma of Community Services	Melbourne Polytechnic	2024
Master of Finance	Monash University	2008
Bachelor of Business (Marketing)	Queensland Uni of Technology	2005

Work Experience

Headspace | Internship - Refugee and Migrant Practice Team | Apr 2024 - Current

- Working on the International Students Experience Project
- Goal is to create culturally and linguistically appropriate mental health resources
- Planning to collaborate with the Participation team for consultation and co-design

Diamond Valley Community Support | Community Support Worker | Nov 2022-2024

Provided emergency relief, material aid, and advocacy services to individuals in crisis

- Delivered friendly, non-judgmental, empathetic, and compassionate support
- Assessed and evaluated clients' needs and developed appropriate support responses
- Completed over 400 client interviews

Thorne Harbour Health | COVID19 Food Delivery Volunteer | May 2020 - Dec 2020

- Delivered food support to socially isolated and immunocompromised LGBTIQ+ clients
- Managed client visits by phoning them in advance to confirm delivery arrangements
- Delivered over 2000 packages to Positive Living Centre clients during the pandemic

Thorne Harbour Health | Sex on Premise Venue Outreach Volunteer | Dec 2018 - Dec 2019

- Provided support to clients at sex-on-premises venues for their health and well-being
- Answered questions about sexual health, HIV, mental health, and substance use
- Suggested appropriate internal and external referrals

Thorne Harbour Health | Re-Wired v2.0 Volunteer Peer Support Facilitator | Aug 2018 - Jan 2019

- SMART Recovery fortnightly meeting for Re-
- Wired program graduates
- Utilised lived experience to assist clients with substance use
- Covered topics such as lapses & relapses, sleep, nutrition, HIV, sex, mental health & mindfulness

Royal Bank of Scotland | Senior Business Analyst | Jan 2016 - Dec 2019

- Lead analyst on regulatory compliance project.
- Successfully established effective collaborations with stakeholders and external organisations.

Independent TV News | Business Analyst | Jan 2014 - Dec 2015

- Lead analyst on a tech project in ITN's Finance dept
- Responsible for creating and managing staff training & project communications
- Supported the project manager in implementing a new accounting software package

National Australia Bank | Project Analyst | Dec 2010 - Dec 2013

- Identified and documented requirements for a new centralised process on a significant transformational change program.
- Designed the solution, drafted appropriate documents, and maintained records per NAB's policies and procedures regarding project delivery.

National Australia Bank | Graduate Program | Jan 2009 - Nov 2010

- Supported manager in managing a portfolio of 100 small business clients
- Clients in Carlton with around \$2 million in borrowings

Licences & Certifications

Working With Children Check	Victorian State Government	2023
First Aid	St John Ambulance Australia	2023
Mental Health First Aid	Mental Health First Aid Australia	2021
SMART Recovery Facilitator	SMART Recovery Australia	2018
Victorian Driver's Licence	VicRoads	2006